Janzhuo Wii

August-Bebel-Str. 17a, 01219 Dresden, Germany

💌 wuhuanzhuo@gmail.com | 🏕 huanzhuo.github.io | 🛅 huanzhuo-wu-4574878b | 🎓 Google Scholar |

Chinese (Native C2), English (Proficient B2), German (Conversational B2)



Profile

I am Huanzhuo Wu, a researcher at the Deutsche Telekom Chair of Communication Networks (ComNets), Technische Universität Dresden (TU Dresden), Germany. My particular research interests are In-network Computing, Software Defined Networks (SDN), and Algorithm Optimization in 5G and beyond, with more than 20 peer-reviewed publications. In addition, I am in charge of applying and managing national funded research projects with leading research institutions and companies. For the latest details about my projects, publications, and activities, please refer to my personal website at https://huanzhuo.github.io or by scanning the QR code in the footer.

Work Experience

Technische Universität Dresden (TU Dresden)

Dresden, Germany

JUNIOR RESEARCHER

Feb. 2017 - Present

- · Conducting research activities on In-network Computing and 5G and beyond networks using SDN and machine learning, with publications, talks, and exhibitions on e.g., IEEE GlobeCom, IEEE ICC, IEEE Internet of Things Journal, CES, and Hanover Messe.
- · Coordinating and managing research projects, in cooperation with Ericsson, Nokia, Robert Bosch GmbH, Huawei Munich Research Center, TU Munich, RWTH Aachen, and other key partners.
- · Applying for funding on research projects, i.e., Exist for research transfer from the Federal Ministry of Economics and Technology Germany (BMWK) in 2022, Software Campus for IT-Talent from the Federal Ministry of Education and Research Germany (BMBF) in 2020.
- · Teaching and supervising students.

Audi China Beijing, China

IT INTERN Aug. 2016 - Nov. 2016 · Managing and supporting projects related to digitalization (Audi Connect, App Center, and Cloud Project).

• Supporting enterprise-university cooperation.

BMW AG Dingolfing, Germany

QUALITY MANAGEMENT INTERN

May. 2015 - Oct. 2015

- Quality management by supporting SAP solutions in the production plant.
- Optimizing and updating the quality management metamodel.
- · Creating quality reports.

Education

Technische Universität Dresden (TU Dresden)

Dresden, Germany

Ph.D. IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

Feb 2017 - Present

- Topic: In-network Audio Processing for Low-latency Industrial Applications.
- Grad Year: Expected October 2022.

Technische Universität Dresden (TU Dresden)

Dresden, Germany

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Apr. 2012 - Dec. 2016

- · Master Thesis: Regenerating Codes.
- Thesis Grade: 1.3.

TUDIAS

Dresden, Germany

GERMAN LANGUAGE COURSE

Aug. 2011 - Mar. 2012

· Final Grade: DSH 2. **Chang'an University**

Xi'an, China

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTE ENGINEERING

Sept. 2007 - July. 2011

- Bachelor Thesis: Wireless Sensor Network.
- Final Grade: A.



Project Experience

6G-Anna funded by BMBF

WITH NOKIA, ERICSSON, AND OTHER KEY PARTNERS

• Contributing to the topic on In-network Computing for 6G systems.

Sept. 2022 - Present

6G-life funded by BMBF

WITH TECHNISCHE UNIVERSITÄT MÜNCHEN (TU MUNICH)

May. 2022 - Present

- · Contributing to the topic on accelerating controlling systems with In-network Computing, using the machine learning scikit-learn.
- · Coordinating and tracking research progress with partners, including research topics and publication plans.

Hexa-X funded by European Commission

WITH NOKIA, ERICSSON, AND OTHER KEY PARTNERS

June. 2021 - Present

- Contributing to the topic on integrating Al into networks, using PyTorch and the network emulator ComNetsEmu.
- Presenting project results on international conferences and journals.

Software Campus Net-BliSS

funded by BMBF

WITH HUAWEI MUNICH RESEARCH CENTER

Mar. 2021 - Present

- Leading the project on In-network Computing for time-sensitive industrial applications, with internal and external partners, as well as reporting to Projektträger DLR.
- Creating project proposal, including research subjects, work plan, manpower, and budget.
- Tracking project progress and maintaining project records.
- Presenting project results at international conferences and exhibitions, e.g., IEEE GlobeCom, IEEE ICC, and CES.
- Training in leadership and management.

5Gang funded by BMBF

WITH ERICSSON, ROBERT BOSCH GMBH, RWTH AACHEN, AND OTHER KEY PARTNERS

Mar. 2017 - Nov.2020

- Responsible for the project on utilizing 5G in the industrial IoT networks, with internal Ph.D. researchers.
- Coordinating with industrial partners, reporting to Projektträger VDI/VDE.
- Tracking project progress and maintaining project records.
- · Presenting project results at international conferences and exhibitions, e.g., IEEE GlobeCom, CES, and Hannover Messe.
- · Organizing and participating in workshops.

Selected Publications

 $The complete publication \ list is available on \ my \ personal \ website \ at \ {\tt https://huanzhuo.github.io} \ or \ via \ the \ {\tt QR} \ code \ in \ the \ footer.$

Journal Articles

- Huanzhuo Wu and Yunbin Shen and Xun Xiao and Giang T. Nguyen and Artur Hecker and Frank H. P. Fitzek, "Accelerating Industrial IoT Acoustic Data Separation with In-Network Computing", In IEEE Internet of Things Journal, pp. 1-15, 2022.
- Jia He and **Huanzhuo Wu** and Xun Xiao and Riccardo Bassoli and Frank H. P. Fitzek, "Functional Split of In-Network Deep Learning for 6G: A Feasibility Study", In IEEE Wireless Communications, pp. 1-7, (submitted, 2022).
- Huanzhuo Wu and Zuo Xiang and Giang T. Nguyen and Yunbin Shen and Frank H. P. Fitzek, "Computing Meets Network: COIN-aware Offloading for Data-intensive Blind Source Separation", In IEEE Network Magazine, 2021.
- Huanzhuo Wu and Giang T. Nguyen and Anil K. Chorppath and Frank H. P. Fitzek, "Network Slicing for Conditional Monitoring in the Industrial Internet of Things", Online IEEE Software Defined Networks, IEEE Softwarization, Jan. 2018.

Conference Papers

- Huanzhuo Wu and Jia He and Máté Tömösközi and Zuo Xiang and Frank H. P. Fitzek, "In-Network Processing for Low-Latency Industrial Anomaly Detection in Softwarized Networks", In 2021 IEEE Global Communications Conference: Next-Generation Networking and Internet (Globecom2021 NGNI), Madrid, Spain, 2021.
- **Huanzhuo Wu** and Yunbin Shen and Xun Xiao and Artur Hecker and Frank H. P. Fitzek, "In-Network Processing Acoustic Data for Anomaly Detection in Smart Factory", In 2021 IEEE Global Communications Conference: IoT and Sensor Networks (Globecom2021 IoTSN), Madrid, Spain, 2021.
- Huanzhuo Wu and Jia He and Máté Tömösközi and Frank H. P. Fitzek, "Abstraction-based Multi-object Acoustic Anomaly Detection for Low-complexity Big Data Analysis", In WS17 IEEE ICC 2021 Workshop on Communication, Computing, and Networking in Cyber-Physical Systems (WS17 ICC'21 Workshop CCN-CPS), Montreal, Canada, 2021.
- Huanzhuo Wu and levgenii A. Tsokalo and David Kußand Hani Salah and Lukas Pingel and Frank H. P. Fitzek, "Demonstration of Network Slicing for Flexible Conditional Monitoring in Industrial IoT Networks", In 2019 16th IEEE Annual Consumer Communications & Networking Conference (CCNC) (CCNC 2019), Las Vegas, USA, 2019.

Book Chapter

• Fabrizio Granelli and Giang T. Nguyen and **Huanzhuo Wu**, "Realizing Network Slicing", In Computing in Communication Networks –From Theory to Practice, Elsevier, vol. 1, pp. 271-289, 2020.

